seatguru.com 2019-12-30

# SeatGuru Privacy Policy

### PRIVACY POLICY

SeatGuru is the ultimate source for airplane seating, in-flight amenities, and airline information. Our Web site is part of the TripAdvisor® Media Group, which is owned and operated by TripAdvisor LLC. More details about SeatGuru can be found below under "How you can contact us." 

We understand that providing information online involves a great deal of trust on your part. We take this trust very seriously, and make it a high priority to ensure the security and confidentiality of the personal information you provide to us. Before submitting your personal information to our Web site, please read this Policy carefully to learn about our privacy practices. By visiting SeatGuru's Web site, www.SeatGuru.com, you are accepting the practices described herein. 

### What information we collect from you

  * In General. We receive and store any information you enter on our Web site or give us in any other way. This includes information that can identify you ("personal information"), including your first and last name, telephone number, postal and e-mail addresses, user name and password. We may also request information about your travel plans, style, and preferences, including meal requests, seat selection, frequent flyer/hotel/car rental program information, and flight class, luggage, and ticketing options. You can choose not to provide information to us, but in general some information about you is required in order for you to enjoy the benefits of being a registered member. For example, only registered members are able to post travel reviews, participate in discussion forums, e-mail SeatGuru content to themselves and others, access members-only newsletters and travel planning content, and enter surveys, contests, or sweepstakes. In addition, some information is also required in order for you to ask us a question or initiate other transactions on our site.
  * Information About Others. You will have the opportunity to provide contact information for other people through our Web site. You should obtain the consent of other individuals prior to providing SeatGuru with their personal information. 
  * Information from Other Sources. We also may periodically obtain both personal and non-personal information about you from affiliated entities, business partners and other independent third-party sources and add it to other information about you. For example, if you visit SeatGuru by "clicking-through" from a site operated by one of our business partners, and you have registered with that partner, then information about you that you have provided to that partner may be shared with us. Examples of other information we may receive include contact information and demographic information. As another example, if you access third party services, such as social media services, through our Web site, we may collect information such as your user name, password, and other information made available to us through those services.
  * Automatic Information. We automatically collect some information about your computer when you visit SeatGuru. For example, we will collect session data, including your IP address, Web browser software, and referring Web site. We also may collect information about your online activity, such as content viewed and pages visited. One of our goals in collecting this automatic information is to help us understand the interests of our users and customize your user experience. 
  * Cookies and Other Web Technologies. Cookies are small data text files and can be stored on your computer's hard drive (if your Web browser permits). SeatGuru.com and its affiliated websites use cookies for the following general purposes: 

    * To help us recognize your browser as a previous visitor and save and remember any preferences that may have been set while your browser was visiting our site. For example, if you register on our site, we may use cookies to remember your registration information, so you do not need to log into our site each time you visit. We also may record your password in a cookie, if you checked the box entitled "Save this password for automatic sign-in." Please note that member IDs, passwords, and any other account-related data included in such cookies are encrypted for security purposes.
    * To help us customize the content, website experience, and advertisements provided to you on our websites and on other websites across the Internet. For example, when you access a web page, a cookie is automatically set by us, our service providers, or our partners to recognize your browser as you navigate on the Internet and to present you with information and advertising based on your apparent interests. See [Display of Advertising/Your Choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) for more information about our online advertising practices and your choices.
    * To help measure and research the effectiveness of website features and offerings, advertisements, and e-mail communications (by determining which e-mails you open and act upon).

The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers should tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable most types of cookies. Please note that if you refuse to accept cookies, you may not be able to access many of the travel tools offered on our sites.

Our sites also may use Web beacons (also known as clear gifs, pixel tags or Web bugs), which are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, that are placed in the code of a Web page. We use Web beacons to monitor the traffic patterns of users from one page within our sites to another, to deliver or communicate with cookies, to understand whether you have come to our site from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party Web site, and to improve site performance. We also may allow our service providers to use Web beacons to help us understand which emails have been opened by recipients and to track the visitor traffic and actions on our site. This helps us measure the effectiveness of our content and other offerings.

  * Display of Advertising/Your Choices

Data collected to serve you with relevant advertising

SeatGuru and its affiliated websites are committed to providing you with relevant content and information across our sites. To do this, we may collect information about your travel-related searches, such as whether you are looking for airline flights or hotels, and use this information to serve you with ads on our sites or elsewhere online that match your apparent interests. So, for example, if you search for information about a flight to Florida on SeatGuru.com, you may see an ad for a Florida travel package on SeatGuru.com or on another website you visit.

We do not share your personal information (such as email addresses) with unaffiliated third parties so they can serve you with advertisements. You can choose not to receive relevant online advertising on other Web sites, based on your travel-related searches on SeatGuru.com by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

Data collected by business partners and ad networks to serve you with relevant advertising

Many of the advertisements you see on the SeatGuru.com sites are served by SeatGuru.com or its service providers. But we also allow third parties to collect information about your online activities through [cookies and other technologies](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). These third parties include (1) business partners, who collect information when you view or interact with one of their advertisements on our sites, and (2) advertising networks, who collect information about your interests when you view or interact with one of the advertisements they place on many different Web sites on the Internet. The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about your characteristics, interests or preferences and to display advertisements on our sites and across the Internet tailored to your apparent interests.

Please note that we do not have access to or control over cookies or other technologies these third parties may use to collect information about your interests, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Some of these companies are members of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/), which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies. To learn more, please click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

### How we use your information

SeatGuru uses the information we collect about you for the following general purposes: for registration and to manage your account, including to facilitate your access to and use of our site; to communicate with you in general, including to provide information about SeatGuru and invitations from the SeatGuru community; to enable us to publish your reviews, forum posts, and other content to the SeatGuru community; to respond to your questions and comments; to measure interest in and improve our products, services, and Web site; to notify you about special offers and products or services available from us or our partners that may be of interest to you; to otherwise customize your experience with SeatGuru; to solicit information from you, including through surveys; to resolve disputes or troubleshoot problems; to prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities; to enforce our Terms of Use; and as otherwise described to you at the point of collection. Please review Your choices with respect to the collection and use of your information below. 

### How you can access your information

We take reasonable steps to ensure that your information is relevant to its intended use, accurate, and complete. You can access and update your contact information by visiting the Member Profile page on the SeatGuru Web site. You can close your SeatGuru account by contacting us at the email address listed below. We will send you an e-mail to confirm your request. Please note that after you close an account, you will not be able to sign in or access any of your personal information. However, you can open a new account at any time. Please also note that we may retain certain information associated with your account in our archives, including for analytical purposes as well as for recordkeeping integrity.

### Your choices with respect to collection and use of your information

As discussed above, you can choose not to provide us with any information, although it may be needed to take advantage of certain features offered on SeatGuru.

You also can add or update information and close your account as described above.

As a registered SeatGuru member, you can modify your e-mail subscription choices at any time on the Member Profile page. Whether registered as a SeatGuru member or not, you also will be given the opportunity to unsubscribe from promotional messages in any such e-mail we send. Please note that we reserve the right to send you other communications, including service announcements, administrative messages, and surveys relating either to your SeatGuru account, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them.

Email Communications. SeatGuru.com wants to make it easy for you to take advantage of travel-related opportunities on our Web site. One way we do this is by sending you e-mail messages that contain information about your apparent travel-related interests. For example, if you search for a flight to New York, or flight reviews on SeatGuru.com, we may send you an email message reminding you about special airfare or travel offers in New York. Similarly, if you receive an email about New York travel and demonstrate an interest in New York flights, or local travel reviews by affirmatively clicking on a link about New York hotels in the email, you may receive an email about New York flight offers. We believe these email messages will provide you with useful information about travel-related special offers available through our sites. Please note that you will have the opportunity to choose not to receive these email messages in any such email we send.

The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Please note that if you refuse to accept cookies from SeatGuru, you will not be able to access portions of our site.

### How we protect your information

We want you to feel confident about using SeatGuru, and we are committed to protecting the information we collect. While no Web site can guarantee security, we have implemented appropriate administrative, technical, and physical security procedures to help protect the personal information you provide to us. For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information, and they only may do so for permitted business functions. In addition, we use encryption when transmitting your personal information between your system and ours, and we employ firewalls and intrusion detection systems to help prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your information.

### Children's privacy

SeatGuru is a general audience site and does not offer services directed to children. Should an individual whom we know to be a child under age 13 send personal information to us, we will delete or destroy such information as soon as reasonably possible.

### External links

If any part of the SeatGuru Web site links you to other Web sites, those external Web sites do not operate under this Privacy Policy. We recommend that you examine the privacy statements posted on those other Web sites to understand their procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing personal information.

### Visiting our Web sites from outside the United States

If you are visiting our Web site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that SeatGuru does take steps pursuant to laws in the United States to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Policy.

### California Consumer Privacy Act Privacy Statement ("CCPA Statement")

This CCPA Statement is provided pursuant to the California Consumer Privacy Act ("CCPA") and applies to California residents and supplements our overall Privacy Statement with additional disclosures and rights.

### Your rights under CCPA

As of January 1 2020, California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their personal information is shared with third-parties or affiliated companies for direct marketing purposes.

California residents may also take advantage of the following rights:

  * You may request, up to two times each year, that we disclose to you the categories and specific pieces of personal information that we have collected about you, the categories of sources from which your personal information is collected, the business or commercial purpose for collecting your personal information, the categories of personal information that we disclosed for a business purpose, any categories of personal information about you that we sold, the categories of third-parties with whom we have shared your personal information, and the business or commercial purpose for selling your personal information, if applicable.
  * You may request that we delete any personal information that we have collected from or about you. As described in more detail in our Privacy Statement, there are some reasons we will not be able to fully address your deletion request, such as if we need to complete a transaction for you, to detect and protect against fraudulent and illegal activity, to exercise our rights, or to comply with a legal obligation.
  * You may request to opt out of our sale of your personal information to third-parties for their direct marketing purposes. This means that, if you opt out, going forward, we will not share your information with such third-parties to use for their purposes unless you later direct us to do so. To effect the opt out, please click on the Do Not Sell My Personal Information link on our website footer or submit a request in writing to the contact information below.

To take advantage of your disclosure and deletion rights, please contact us via email at privacy@tripadvisor.com. We may need to verify your identity to enable us to process your request. We value your privacy and will not discriminate in response to your exercise of privacy rights. We will respond to your request within 45 days of receipt of your request, after proper verification, unless we need additional time, in which case we will let you know.

### Disclosures

For purposes of compliance with the CCPA, in addition to the further details as described in the Statement, we make the following disclosures:

  * We collect the following categories of personal information: _Identifiers/Contact Information, transactional information, Internet or other electronic network activity information, geolocation, visual and audio information, and inferences drawn from the above._
  * We sell the following categories of personal information: _Identifiers/Contact Information, Internet or other electronic network activity information, and inferences drawn from the above._
  * We disclose the following categories of personal information for a business purpose: _Identifiers/Contact Information, commercial information, Internet or other electronic network activity information, geolocation, visual and audio information, and inferences drawn from the above._

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

SeatGuru may update this Privacy Policy in the future. We will notify our members about material changes to this Privacy Policy by either sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us or by placing a prominent notice on our Web site.

### How you can contact us

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:  
Email: [privacy@tripadvisor.com](mailto:privacy@tripadvisor.com)  
TripAdvisor LLC  
400 1st Avenue  
Needham, MA 02494 

This Privacy Policy is effective as of January 1, 2020.
